<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: dura, | ]]></title>
  <link href="http://wholeslide.com/blog/categories/dura/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://wholeslide.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-04T21:38:57-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://wholeslide.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Rich Stoner]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Building the index]]></title>
    <link href="http://wholeslide.com/blog/2014/02/18/building-the-index/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-18T12:48:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://wholeslide.com/blog/2014/02/18/building-the-index</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This post will provide a high-level view of the indexing approach used by the DURA remote data source.</p>

<p><em>The DURA remote data source is simply a standalone elasticsearch server running somewhere in digitalocean.</em></p>

<h4>General data model</h4>

<p>A dura object has a few key properties:</p>

<ol>
<li>title</li>
<li>short description</li>
<li>type &ndash;> the corresponding class in the dura data model</li>
<li>json description</li>
</ol>


<p>To get search to work, I should add additional tags that enable me to slice across different facets.</p>

<p>For example, I would like to predefine queries for:</p>

<ul>
<li>Species</li>
</ul>


<p>For species, I would return any matching content type that is from an organism matching the species string.</p>

<ul>
<li>General content type</li>
</ul>


<p>For general content type, this would allow me to search for &lsquo;all electron microscopy volumes&rsquo; or &lsquo;all zoomify images&rsquo; or &lsquo;all course lists&rsquo;.</p>

<h4>Thinking aloud</h4>

<p>Adding relational search via graph-based mappings, while fun, is beyond the difficulty level of what I&rsquo;m trying for …Although, it would open up the opportunity to do some great mappings, and possibly give me some overlap between the INCF NI-DM and DURA.</p>

<p>Everything on the collections page will be a search. Everything in the defaults.json generated by ipy will be a search query, description, and icon.</p>

<h4>Steps to replace the current defaults</h4>

<ol>
<li>Index the defaults in elasticsearch</li>
<li>Write pre-canned query</li>
<li>Write pre-canned query generator</li>
<li>Rebuild defaults.json</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[EM Navigation]]></title>
    <link href="http://wholeslide.com/blog/2014/02/18/em-navigation/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-18T12:43:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://wholeslide.com/blog/2014/02/18/em-navigation</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A quick demo of Dura, the core application behind WholeSlide Open. We&rsquo;re quickly working towards a v1.0</p>

<iframe src="http://wholeslide.com//player.vimeo.com/video/80876206" width="500" height="652" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p> <p><a href="http://vimeo.com/80876206">Open Viewer With EM annotation alpha</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/wholeslide">Rich Stoner</a> on <a href="https://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p></p>

<h4>What can it do now? (build ~#4000)</h4>

<ul>
<li>View high resolution image sets from Brainmaps.org (uses boring 2D viewer, 3d in progress)</li>
<li>Link with Dropbox (sandboxed currently, needs appstore submission before this will work)</li>
<li>Connect to Knossos (EM) image services (experimental, issues with VRAM and opengl es 2)</li>
<li>Connect to OpenConnectome (EM) servers (experimental, issues with VRAM and opengl es 2)</li>
<li>Open converted EyeWire neuron meshes (experimental, issues with VRAM and opengl es 2)</li>
</ul>


<h4>What will it do in the future?</h4>

<ul>
<li>Connect to Aperio image servers</li>
<li>Contain most of the image resources available in the original WholeSlide app.</li>
<li>Connect to MicroBrightField&rsquo;s Biolucida Server.</li>
<li>Connect to data stored on remote hard drives</li>
<li>View and create annotations on high resolution images</li>
<li>View stacks of high resolution images in 3D</li>
<li>Visualize skeletonized annotations for EM</li>
<li>Visualize volume annotations for EM</li>
<li>Include data sources beyond neuroscience (dermatology, radiology)</li>
<li>Integrate a searchable backend</li>
<li>Create courses and link content together</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
